https://www.baldwins.co.uk/privacy-policy

We use cookies to give you the best possible experience. To accept cookies continue browsing, or view our Cookies Policy to find out more.
Allow Cookies
RemediesHairCoarseDamaged / Split EndsSkinCelluliteDermatitisSun DamageSun ProtectionHealthAllergiesBladder Control / UTIBlood & CirculationBone Strength & DentalBreathing ConditionsClarityDigestion & HeartburnExhaustion & FatigueFertilityLibidoMemoryMenopauseMuscle & Joint PainPMS / Menstrual IssuesSleep AidsWeight LossVeganHeadaches & Stress ReliefClarityMemoryCold, Cough & FluAnti-InflammatoryCold & FluCoughSeasonal RemediesHay FeverInsect BitesInsecticide & Insect RepellentSun DamageSun ProtectionAromatherapyEssential OilsAromatherapy OilsOrganic Essential OilsPre-Diluted Essential OilsBalsamsStorage BoxesAromatherapy Boxed SetsCarrier OilsCarrier OilsMacerated OilsBase ProductsBaldwins Base ProductsOlive Tree Base ProductsOrganic Base ProductsFloral WatersSynergyBody & Bath OilsBody Washes, Balms & LotionsShampoos & ConditionersSoapsFace OilsAromatherapy Gift PacksAroma Roll OnsBottles & JarsAlpha Bottles (Amber Glass)Beta Bottles (Amber Glass)Bottles & Jars (Plastic)Plastic (PET) Bottles & JarsPlastic JerricansJars (Dark & Clear Glass)Lids & Caps (Plastic)Lip-Balm Tins (Aluminium)Measures (Bomex Or Plastic)Reagent Jars (Amber / Clear Glass)Roll On Bottles (Glass)Sample Jars (Plastic)Sprays & Pumps (Plastic)Syrup Bottles (Amber Glass)Winchester (Amber Glass)Aromatherapy CandlesOil Burners & DiffusersAromatherapy BooksHerbsHerbs, Roots & BarksHerbs, Roots & BarksHerb, Root & Bark PowdersOrganic HerbsChinese HerbsIndian HerbsHerb SeedsMushroomsTincturesStandard TincturesChineseIndianA. Vogel RangeFluid ExtractsAlcohol Free ExtractsStandard ExtractsHerbal Tea BagsHeath And HeatherDalgetyDr Stuart'sSalus HouseYogi TeasClipperD.Atkinson HerbalistTea AccessoriesCapsules & TabletsHerbal Capsules & TabletsEmpty CapsulesCapsule MachinesCreams & OintmentsSouth AmericanBitterstern Herbal BittersSwedish BittersGumsIncenseCharcoalIncense GrainsSmudge SticksIncense SticksWaxes & ButtersOther ProductsHerb BooksAyurvedicHair & SkinFaceCleansersFace WashTonersMoisturisersEye CareLip CareMasks, Scrubs & PeelsFacial Oils & SerumSkin MistsBath & BodyBath OilsMassage & Body OilsFoaming Bath & SaltsShower GelBody Balms & CreamsHand & Foot CareSun CareBath AccessoriesHairShampoosConditionersHenna PowderHerbatintFlash FashionHenne Hair ColoursToiletriesSoapOral CareDeodorantSplashes & ColognesMensBaby SkincareAloe VeraSupplements & EssencesVitamins & MineralsMultivitaminsVitamin AVitamin BVitamin CVitamin DVitamin EVitamin KMineralsMother & ChildTonicsAntioxidantsEssential Fatty AcidsLecithinDigestive Health & CleansingAloe VeraCleanse & DetoxDigestive HealthProbioticsHair Skin & NailsJoint HealthSports & Amino AcidsAmino AcidsProtein PowdersSuperfoodsGreen FoodsSuperfood JuicesFlower EssencesFindhorn Flower EssencesAustralian Bush EssencesIndividual EssencesCombination DropsOral SpraysLight Frequency EssencesWhite Light EssencesSkin & Space MistsOrganic MoisturisersAlaskan EssencesBach Flower EssencesRescue RemedyIndividual RemediesSetsStarryHeartWhite Light EssencesLight Frequency EssencesJan De Vries EssencesHomeopathyRemediesCreams, Ointments & BalmsTissue SaltsTerranovaWomen's HealthMen's HealthBee ProductsCapsule MakingHemp ProductsHemp BodycareHemp FoodsHemp OilsCraftsBase ProductsCarrier OilsMacerated OilsBase ProductsSoap MakingPure SoapCandle MakingBooks, CD's & MoreEssencesAromatherapyDiet & NutritionHerbs & HerbalismNatural CraftsSoap MakingSpecial InterestCharts & PostersSelf Help CDsCapsulesEmpty CapsulesCapsule MachinesBottles & JarsAlpha Bottles (Amber Glass)Beta Bottles (Amber Glass)Bottles & Jars (Plastic)Jars (Glass)Lids & Caps (Plastic)Lip-Balm Tins (Aluminium)Measures (Bomex Or Plastic)Reagent Jars (Glass)Sample Jars (Plastic)Sprays & Pumps (Plastic)Syrup Bottles (Amber Glass)Winchesters (Amber Glass)Lotion MakingFood, Drink & HouseholdHealthy LivingYoga MatsBamboo Charcoal Health ProductsNeti PotsHealth FoodCereals & PastasCondimentsBakeryOils & VinegarsSeasoningsDried FruitOrganic Dried FruitDried FruitBakingFloursGrains & PulsesGrainsPulsesJuices & DrinksNuts & SeedsOrganic Nuts & SeedsNuts & SeedsSoya & Milk AlternativesSpreads & HoneysHoney & SyrupsNut & Seed ButtersPreserves & SpreadsSugar & SweetenersSweets & SnacksTeas & BeveragesMushrooms & FunghiCooking OilsBreadHouseholdCandlesCleaningCookingSprouters & SeedsBath AccessoriesHome & Cooking BooksFeminine HygieneMother & BabyBrandsA.VogelAfrocenchixAlaskan EssencesAlvaAnton HubnerAustralian Bush Flower EssencesBach Flower RemediesBamboo CharcoalBarefoot BotanicalsBee Brand - Minyak GosokBenjaminsBentley OrganicBetter YouBio-HealthBionaBiosnackyBiosunBiottaBittersternBraggsClearspringClipper TeasComvitaDalgetyDead Sea Spa MagikDiet HorizonDoves FarmDr BronnerDr Stuart'sDragonfly TeasEleven O'ClockEncens d'AurovilleEqual ExchangeFaith In NatureFindhornFSC - The Food Supplement CompanyFushi Wellbeing Ltd.Granary HerbsGreen PeopleGolden Greens Organic SuperfoodsHay MaxHeath & HeatherHeliosHenne ColorHerbatintHigher NatureHope's ReliefHouse Of MistryIncognitoInfinity FoodsJan de VriesJoanna NaturalsJohn ChamberKalloKingfisherKlamathLaughing BirdLepicolLewtressLifeplanLifestreamLight Frequency EssencesLily Of The DesertLinwoodsMade By ZenMeridianMilton BrookNag ChampaNanny Goat MilkNatracareNature Knows BestNature's AidNature's AnswerNature's OwnNature's PlusNelsonsBalancing Neroli & Willow Bark SkincareNew Era - Mineral Cell SaltsNutivaObbekjaersOlbas OilOlive TreeOptibacOrtisPaynes Southdown Bee FarmsPlamilPomegranate, Bilberry & RosePottersPower HealthPrewett'sProvamelPukka HerbsPulsinPure IncensePure Papaya OintmentQi TeasQuestRabenhorstRio HealthRobert GrayRocks CordialsRude HealthSalt Of The EarthSalusSeagreensShady MapleSkin BlossomSolaraySoloSt.Ann MoringaSt.DalfourStream2Sea Sun CareStute JuicesSukin Australian SkincareSunitaSwissSymingtonsSynergyTerranovaThe Konjac Sponge CoTheraneemThorncroftTiger BalmTraidcraftUdo's ChoiceUnBeelievable HealthVegetalViridianWeledaWild NutritionYaohYogi
Menu
Remedies
Hair
Coarse
Damaged / Split Ends
Skin
Cellulite
Dermatitis
Bottles & Jars
Alpha Bottles (Amber Glass)
Beta Bottles (Amber Glass)
Bottles & Jars (Plastic)
Plastic (PET) Bottles & Jars
Plastic Jerricans
Jars (Dark & Clear Glass)
Lids & Caps (Plastic)
Lip-Balm Tins (Aluminium)
Measures (Bomex Or Plastic)
Reagent Jars (Amber / Clear Glass)
Roll On Bottles (Glass)
Sample Jars (Plastic)
Sprays & Pumps (Plastic)
Syrup Bottles (Amber Glass)
Winchester (Amber Glass)
Aromatherapy Candles
Oil Burners & Diffusers
Aromatherapy Books
Herbs
Herbs, Roots & Barks
Herbs, Roots & Barks
Herb, Root & Bark Powders
Organic Herbs
Bottles & Jars
Alpha Bottles (Amber Glass)
Beta Bottles (Amber Glass)
Bottles & Jars (Plastic)
Jars (Glass)
Lids & Caps (Plastic)
Lip-Balm Tins (Aluminium)
Measures (Bomex Or Plastic)
Reagent Jars (Glass)
Sample Jars (Plastic)
Sprays & Pumps (Plastic)
Syrup Bottles (Amber Glass)
Winchesters (Amber Glass)
Lotion Making
Food, Drink & Household
Healthy Living
Yoga Mats
Bamboo Charcoal Health Products
Neti Pots
Health Food
Cereals & Pastas
FSC - The Food Supplement Company
Fushi Wellbeing Ltd.
Granary Herbs
Green People
Golden Greens Organic Superfoods
Hay Max
Heath & Heather
Helios
Henne Color
Herbatint
INTRODUCTION
This is the Baldwins privacy policy notice.
Baldwins respects your privacy and is committed to protecting your personal data. This privacy notice will inform you how we look after your personal data and tell you about your privacy rights and how the General Data Protection Regulation 2016 (GDPR) protects you.
1.          IMPORTANT INFORMATION AND WHO WE ARE
1.1        PURPOSE OF THIS PRIVACY NOTICE
This privacy notice aims to give you information on how Baldwins collects and processes your personal data through your use of our website or any other correspondence.
It is important that you read this privacy notice together with any other privacy notice or fair processing notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This privacy notice supplements the other notices and is not intended to override them.
1.2        CONTROLLER
G Baldwin and Co Ltd (company number: 04639383 ) having its registered office at 171-173 Walworth Road, London, SE17 1RW  is the controller and responsible for your personal data (collectively referred to as Baldwins, “we”, “us” or “our” in this privacy notice).
If you have any questions about this privacy notice, including any requests to exercise your rights, please contact the Baldwins using the details set out below.
1.3        CONTACT DETAILS
Full name of legal entity: G Baldwin and Co Ltd
Email address: support@baldwins.co.uk
Postal address:   171-173 Walworth Road, London, SE17 1RW
You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues (https://ico.org.uk/). We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please contact us in the first instance.
1.4        CHANGES TO THE PRIVACY NOTICE AND YOUR DUTY TO INFORM US OF CHANGES
This version was last updated on 22th May 2018,and will be reviewed at least annually or as circumstances require.
It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us.
1.5        THIRD-PARTY LINKS
Our website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements.
THE DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU
Personal data is any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).
We may collect, use, store, share and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together as follows:
Identity Data includes first name, last name, username or similar identifier and title.
Contact Data includes billing address, delivery address, email address and telephone numbers.
Technical Data includes internet protocol (IP) address, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access this website.
Usage Data includes information about how you use our website.
Marketing and Communications Data includes your preferences in receiving marketing from us and your communication preferences.
Aggregated Data includes statistical or demographic data for any purpose. It may be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data does not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific feature.
We do not collect any Special Categories of Personal Data about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.
HOW IS YOUR PERSONAL DATA COLLECTED?
We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:
Direct interactions. You may give us your Identity and Contact Data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise.
Automated technologies or interactions. If you interact with our website, we may automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies, server logs and other similar technologies. Please see our cookie policy in paragraph 8 below for further details.
Third parties or publicly available sources. We may receive personal data about you from various third parties and public sources as set out below
Technical Data from the following parties:
(a)  analytics providers such as Google based outside the EU.
(b)  search information providers such as Google, Yahoo or Firefox based inside or outside the EU.
HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA
We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:
Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.
Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests. This means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service/product and the best and most secure experience. We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law).
Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.
Where you have given your consent to us to process your personal data.
5.PURPOSES FOR WHICH WE WILL USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA
We have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate.
Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please Contact us if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below.
Purpose/Activity
Type of data
Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest
To register you as a new customer
(a) Identity
(b) Contact
Performance of a contract with you
To process and deliver your order including:
(a) Manage payments, fees and charges
(b) Collect and recover money owed to us
(a) Identity
(b) Contact
(c) Financial
(d) Transaction
(e) Marketing and Communications
(a) Performance of a contract with you
(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to recover debts due to us)
To manage our relationship with you which will include:
(a) Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy
(a) Identity
(b) Contact
(c) Profile
(d) Marketing and Communications
(a) Performance of a contract with you
(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation
(c) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products/services)
To administer and protect our business (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data)
(a) Identity
(b) Contact
(c) Technical
(a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise)
(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation
To deliver relevant website content
(a) Identity
(b) Contact
(c) Profile
(d) Usage
(e) Marketing and Communications
(f) Technical
Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy)
To use data analytics to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences
(a) Technical
(b) Usage
Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy)
To make suggestions and recommendations to you about goods or services that may be of interest to you
(a) Identity
(b) Contact
(c) Technical
(d) Usage
(e) Profile
Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our products/services and grow our business)
MARKETING
We strive to provide you with choices regarding certain personal data uses, particularly around marketing and advertising.
We may use your Identity, Contact, Technical, Usage and Profile Data to form a view on what we think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which products, services and offers may be relevant for you (we call this marketing).
You will receive marketing communications from us if you have requested information from us or purchased services from us and, in each case, you have not opted out of receiving that marketing.
OPTING OUT
You can ask us to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by Contacting us at any time. Where you opt out of receiving these marketing messages, this will not apply to personal data provided to us as a result of a product/service purchase, warranty registration, product/service experience or other transactions.
COOKIES
Cookies are small text files - containing letters and numbers - which are downloaded by your computer when you access and use certain websites. Cookies allow our Website to recognise a device and provide content accordingly. We recommend that you accept all cookies from our Website, as they have been designed to enhance the service that this Website provides you.
If you choose to disable any of these cookies, then you may impair the functionality of the Website and you may not experience all its features in the way it was designed to be enjoyed. To disable cookies, we suggest that you set your browser to disable cookies for https://www.baldwins.co.uk. This option usually appears under "Tools" or "Settings" in a section called "Privacy" and is intuitive. Browsers implement this feature differently, so please refer to your browser help section for detailed information. Or, search the internet for "Disabling cookies with X browser" where X is your browser name.
For more information about cookies and how they are used on the internet, please see the information on the independent All About Cookies site and the Wikipedia article on HTTP Cookies.
Google Analytics cookies used on this site
Google Analytics is a free service provided by Google that uses several cookies. The cookies set by Google Analytics are used to help us gather information about how this website is used by visitors. The information is not personally identifiable and is simply used to track and improve the level of service our Website is providing. More information on the cookies that are set through our use of Google Analytics can be found on Google's Cookies & Google Analytics page. If you wish to disable these cookies, please use the opt-out browser add-on supplied by Google. Or you can set your browser to reject all or certain cookies. Disabling cookies set by Google Analytics will not reduce the service provided to you.
CHANGE OF PURPOSE
We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please Contact us.
If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.
Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.
DISCLOSURES OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA
We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out in the table in paragraph 5 above:
External Third Parties: service providers, partners and sub-contractors based in the EU or Worldwide, professional advisers (e.g. lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers based in the EU,
Third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this privacy notice.
Other parties such as HM Revenue & Customs and law enforcement agencies where we are under a duty to comply with a legal obligation, or to protect our rights, or to protect the rights, property or safety of Baldwins, our customers or others.
We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.
11.    INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS
We do not transfer your personal data outside the European Economic Area (EEA).
12.    DATA SECURITY
We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.
We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.
13.    DATA RETENTION- HOW LONG WILL YOU USE MY PERSONAL DATA FOR?
We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.
To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.
In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see Request erasure below for further information.
In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.
14.    YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS
You have a right to:
Request access to your personal data (commonly known as a “ subject access request”). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.
Request rectification of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.
Request erasure of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.
Object to processing of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.
Request restriction of processing of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data’s accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.
Request the transfer of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.
Withdraw consent at any time where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.
If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above you may submit a Subject Access Request Please Contact us.
You will not have to pay a fee to submit a subject access request (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.
What we may need from you.  We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.
Time Limit to respond. We will respond to all legitimate requests within one month.
Get in Touch with Us
We always love to hear from you whether you are looking for further information or need help using our site, feel free to contact us.
Get in Touch
Can’t find what you’re looking for?
Call our expert customer service team on 020 7703 5550 or use our contact page.
Contact Us
As featured in Time Out
At number 64, our Walworth Road Shops are featured in Time out London’s
100 best shops and we couldn’t be more delighted!
Read More
Material Safety Data Sheets
All the information you need to use our products safely.
Read More
Receive Our Catalogue
View our Catalogue online or request one to your home.
It is stocked full of our latest oils, beauty products, health foods & gifts.
Request Now
